Hello! I would be very grateful if you would consider my question!
Can a raster approach be effective in supervised learning?

The SVM or ANN methods perform search of a surface which would divide data points in a best way. This surface is returned in the vector or parametric form. I try to implement the method that returns a spatial bitmap with the adaptive grid each voxel of which contains a numeric value defining a class for all points lying within this voxel. To obtain such bitmap all data points are represented by the certain RBF, allowing to adjust the range of influence of each data point. The sum of all RBFs is calculated in some number of points, lying within the given voxel. The given voxel then can be tessellated depending on the analysis of the calculated values. The main goal of the adaptive grid is to capture the all boundary points (for binary classification these are the points in which the sum of RBFs is close to zero) while maintaining the computational resources at an affordable level.

Taking the first step in this direction, I received encouraging performance results with the dummy data (https://youtu.be/Cp7wI2BTWIs) and with the one real dataset (). The algorithm used is capable of processing data points in batch mode having no significant impact to a final result. Obviously, more tests are required to draw conclusions about the effectiveness of this method. Since I'm relatively new in machine learning I can't be quite sure that this was not done before. Perhaps there are some reasons that are obscure to me which make this approach meaningless for real data.

I would be very grateful if I got some direction from your team! Many thanks for your attention!

1. The certain RBF, representing each data point, is used with the adaptive grid which stores the sum of all the RBFs in each voxel. 

Perhaps, there are some reasons, making this approach meaningless for real data but taking the first step in this direction, I received encouraging performance results with dummy data () and with one real dataset (). 